Oh.
These predators
that are out here
just get closer and
closer and closer.
If I'm gonna die, I'm
gonna die fighting.
Look at that.
You're starting hunter,
and I'm backup hunter.
20 days into the
35 day challenge...
Why am I wasting so much energy?
...the pressure on the remaining
eight survivalists is mounting.
Holy crap.
-Whoa!
-Oh, oh!
Oh, I see it. Yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
As Teal took over
the hunting duties...
Maybe this thing is
sick or heat exhausted,
but we have to eat.
...and landed a major
protein score for the team.
Nice, fresh red meat.
-Cheers.
I can't believe how
well we're thriving.
We're so set up now.
-Oh, my God!
-Jesus Christ.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Teal, look through here.
-What are these tracks?
-Ooh!
Oh, my goodness.
It's a cat of some sort.
See it? Is it a paw?
Yeah, they do
look like paw prints.
See, look right there, too.
This is so close to our shelter.
Our boma is right there.
That's 40 yards away.
So these things
are walking around
right where we're living.
Yeah, they're everywhere.
This place has
looked after us so well,
but that dynamic is
changing quite fast.
There's so many predators
that are stalking around
and looking for meals.
It's definitely something
that's front of mind
that they wanna
take this territory back.
Oh, my gosh.
It's heating up already.
I can't believe it.
Shoot, sun's only been
up for an hour or two.
Oh, Teal, look through here.
-Another kudu cow.
-Oh, my goodness.
There are flies
everywhere on this.
This is a few days old at least.
Well past the
point we can eat it.
I'm sure the inside of that
is just millions of maggots.
Dude, there's something
about this place.
It's just completely unnatural.
Even the things that
are supposed to live here
can't survive.
Yeah, it just speaks volumes
to this, uh, the environment,
how brutal it is, and
how savage it is out here.
Africa's not even
a match for itself.
This could be a
bad spot to be in.
All the preys left and
we are the only ones left
on the dinner menu.
Everything's been wiped out.
All right, team, stay strong.
Good luck on the hunt.
Yep, good luck out there, man.
Hell yeah.
Team Thunder
Bone, love you guys.
Here we go.
Yes! That's a big one.
After his second food
win, of the challenge...
Hey, guys, you
ready for breakfast?
Look at this guy.
Scoring protein, that's
what I'm all about.
...Frank has turned to
more primitive methods
to keep providing for the team.
He's gonna peck at this,
and then, boom,
you get a guinea.
It's gonna be a cooker today.
Not a single cloud in the sky.
It's gotta be in the '90s
already today, which is crazy.
I'm gonna sit in this
blind for about three,
four hours today.
Hopefully,
something comes
down and takes a drink.
We need to get some
more food on the table.
If we get one big win,
that pretty much carries us
to the end.
All right, I just got set
up in my ground blind.
This is the second water source.
Gives us the opportunity
for them to show up,
so maybe I can provide
some food for my team.
It's a waiting game.
We're gonna get
roasted out here.
I know, it's hot.
That's lost quite
a bit of water.
Yup, hopefully a couple
more days might start seeing
catfish, like, in the mud.
We're almost three
weeks into this challenge,
and, you know,
food's running low.
We did have an impala score
earlier on, which was crucial,
but it's been a while
since we've made a kill
or caught a fish.
We've got traps
deployed right now,
so just gotta figure
out what works.
Now, let's see.
This one is still set,
and the bait is still there.
Oh.
Just, uh, I just don't
think they've been by it
or just haven't seen it yet.
OK.
So the second one is over here.
It's right up here.
Now that is still set.
-Yeah.
-But the bait is gone.
The bait's gone.
Maybe this spring pole
has too much tension.
Maybe lighter tension
will help it go off easier.
OK.
It is so frustrating
because I've provided
the protein for
my family out here,
pretty much through the
whole challenge, you know?
So we'll just redo this.
And let's see what happens.
Frank is my buddy.
He always will be.
We came in together.
We're gonna go out together.
He has endless patience.
OK, now let's bait this thing.
I'm gonna use a piece
of the sinew to tie him
-to that bait stick.
-OK.
Now hold that bait stick
right here, let go the wings.
Here we go... bait.
He's just incredibly
generous with his knowledge
and, you know, it really
is a "hurry up and wait."
At some point, something is
gonna walk into those traps,
and the more of them
that are out there,
-the better odds that we have.
-It's already hot.
Sure is.
This reminds me of
a blacktop parking lot
in June in Florida.
You can feel that heat.
Ooh, there's a big snake skin.
It's about the size we
don't wanna run into, right?
Yeah, exactly that.
Especially with the black mamba.
Ugh, that's great.
After Wes and Steve's
first big food win went bad...
What the hell is that?
Oh! Disgusting. That's bad.
It's gotta go.
Holy.
...things took a dangerous
turn at their camp.
Whoa!
Sort of scared it away.
It's a snake.
-Right next to ya.
-Oh, my God.
Black mamba.-!
It's a black mamba.
He bites you and you're
dead, and he was in our shelter.
When something
like that happens,
you have a moment of
reflection, and you go,
"What in the hell
am I doing here?"
Oh, man, oh, man.
It's been a tough few days.
Yep. Unbelievable.
There are so many dangerous
things in South Africa.
I mean, all of a sudden,
I had a black mamba
one foot from my head.
And so the risk reward
factor is really in play.
But for right now, I keep
going, just push through,
and hope for a little
bit of luck, honestly.
Hey, Stee, guess
what I'm looking at?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
So right on the bank.
Right there, you
see the checkered.
Ah, damn.
It's very defeating.
Yeah.
To a degree.
No meal today.
It's really a rough situation.
We've probably tried seven
different things to catch fish.
And it's just disappointing
when you keep coming
up empty handed.
He is.
-Give us a break.
-Yeah.
I tell you, I am
hungry, and I'm getting
-a little bit perturbed, too.
-Yeah.
Something has gotta give.
Nice.
Well, wriggly tin.
Day or two, we
slam it right here,
and then this
whole part is ours.
Yeah, so, if we can bring
all the down at one time,
If we put it in now, then
we'll have the benefits of it.
-Yeah, when the water drains...
-Three, four, five days later.
-Yeah.
Yep.
It's absolutely
beating the out of us.
All right, so we're
gonna check the fish trap.
See, hopefully there's
some terrapin in there.
What you got next
for me, Mother Nature?
He's a lone bull Stalked
by a large elephant...
...and struggling
with lack of food...
Starting to get
a little blackout.
...Joe's fish track
finally paid off.
Absolutely incredible.
With me getting that
small mule, it gets me by,
but I've been working
my body and my muscles,
especially... to the bone,
and I'm getting
weaker a lot faster.
Come on, baby.
Been solo surviving
for 16 days now.
It's incredibly difficult
to survive all alone.
That's a bummer.
To be able to do all the
things a team of three
has to do in this stressful
an environment, you know,
mentally and physically,
is just wearing me down.
Switching gears, real quick.
I'm gonna jump back in the blind
and, uh, hunt for
the rest of the day.
This is my number one priority.
To score a big meal right
now would definitely ensure
getting through the
next, uh, 15 days.
Let's keep the sun
off of us a little bit.
Been sitting this blind
regularly for a few days now,
and I haven't seen a large game.
The elephant that's been
stalking and thrashing my blind
and around my home,
crashing and thrashing
through the night,
is such a bully.
He's a big animal,
but I'm a big dude too.
Right now, I'm
feeling dangerous.
Keep away, mother.
That's right.
Keep on walking, buddy.
I wanted to protect my blind.
I've been sitting here hoping
that this hunting ground
would turn out, and I
don't want to surrender it.
I stood up to the big
baddie, my big foe out here.
That elephant needed
the reminder who's really
in charge out here,
and I stared him down.
That he ended up
turning and walking away.
I roar at lions, and I
stare down elephants,
and don't you forget it.
Home, sweet home.
Maybe we should stop
and just take a big drink.
Yeah, let's do that. Let's
stop in the shade over here.
OK.
Teal and I, we've
done a lot of work
to get where we are, this place,
from a survival perspective,
it's treated us so well.
But that dynamic's
shifting a little bit
because of how much
the environment's changing
around here.
There's no animals
around here anymore.
They've moved
on to better places.
So, I was thinking, we've got
around about two weeks left
and we have this really
long journey ahead of us,
so what I was thinking was,
I don't think staying right
here for as long as possible
is the best option.
What are your thoughts on it?
Yeah, wow, that's
like a huge decision.
Potentially, we're just
subjecting ourselves to worse.
Yeah, but we have to
leave here eventually.
Let's leave here
when we're in the
strongest position possible.
If we wait until we're
in a weak position,
it's gonna be real tough.
I see what you're saying.
If we just dwindle
down our food supply.
By the time we need to make
it, we're gonna have less energy
-to do so.
-Mm-hmm.
The idea of leaving this place
is a hard thing to swallow,
but us leaving here
is just one step closer
to getting the heck out
of this wasteland.
Oh, you still got that map?
Yeah, so, to escape this
place, we have to make it
all the way up here.
That's a huge journey.
So, what I was thinking
is, we'll break it into two.
Those are extra water sources
that we can touch on the way,
so I'm not worried
about the water.
Currently, six miles from
their original drop point,
Waz and Teal remain over
20 miles from the northern
perimeter of the wasteland,
which they'll have to
cross over into civilization
on day 35.
Today's prep.
Tomorrow's go time.
Yeah, we need to make sure
we're hydrating like
crazy up to that point
when we're moving.
All part of the way out.
That's it.
Escape this wasteland.
What stuff here
are we considering
valuable enough
to carry with us?
Well, I think the
pliers have to go.
100%, yep.
And... The knife, obviously.
The hammer. Fire
starter, for sure.
Yeah, that.
We are getting ready
to make our big trek.
So the tools that we've
decided to bring are gonna be
the ones we've been
most reliant on to survive.
We can't risk not having
this type of stuff available
at the next location.
I think as much wire as
we can take with us as well.
We might not have to use
it, but it's pretty lightweight,
and it can come in handy
if we do have to use it.
We've done a lot of
work to get where we are,
and we're gonna have to
walk away from that tomorrow,
which is a tough thing to do.
There are some concerns.
We don't know what our
resources are gonna be like.
A lot of the man-made stuff
that's been keeping us dry
and keeping us warm,
that's getting left behind.
Uh, but it's a journey that
we have to take eventually,
so it's better that we
dictate exactly when it is
that we take that journey.
All right, I think
that's a good plan.
Let's do it.
Whew.
-What's up, fam?
-Hi.
Not a single
thing. Not a guinea.
No new tracks.
You know, so did you
guys check the traps?
Mm-hmm.
All right, I'm gonna hydrate
and chill for a while
because it is scorching
-out right now.
-100% It is a hot one today.
It's gotta be in the hundreds.
And sometimes the best thing
you can do is sit in the shade
and take a breather.
I know it's hot.
But, you know, I
gotta keep hunting.
I don't know if
that's a great idea.
Like, in the middle of
the day, it's gonna be
-like 115 degrees today.
-Yeah.
I believe you.
But we've been
several, several days
with no fresh meat,
no fresh anything.
We can't keep this up, you know?
Yeah.
All right, so I guess
I'm gonna get ready
-to go hunting.
-Take it easy.
-All right.
-Stay safe.
All right, I shall see you
guys when I get back.
-All right.
-Good luck, Godspeed.
So I'm walking out
in the heat of the day.
But it's a necessary risk,
and it's one I have to take
for my team and myself.
You know, we need food.
We need protein.
Yeah, so Stee and I
go fishing this morning,
and the first thing
we notice is the croc.
It's back, competing for food.
So we decided we're
gonna take some wriggly tin
and build a dam.
Along the narrowest
part of their creek,
Wes and Steve's
strategy is to repurpose
scavenged roofing tin,
old lumber, and rocks
to build a makeshift
dam that will keep
the crocodile on one side
while creating shallower waters
and better fishing
conditions on the other.
Care for your ankles.
Lot of little stones.
Can you see the croc anywhere?
Oh yeah, he's way
down there for right now.
Try to go as straight
across as you can.
With as high as it's
been lately, we figure
in a few days, that
smaller part may dry up,
like almost completely.
And at that point, if we
have catfish trapped up there,
we can just walk
out and pick them up.
What we can do is get
loads of trees and rocks,
-then lean them on it.
-Sure.
But we really need
to make this happen.
Look at this one, solid.
OK.
We'll just keep staking it out.
Can you see the croc?
Yeah, I see him.
He did go under.
-He went under?
-He went under.
A lot closer than
I've ever seen it.
Jeez, it take to get a catfish.
We need to get this done.
We need to stop talking
about it, and we need
to actually just get it done.
Let's finish the sticks.
Just sharpen some
sticks and get me those.
-Then we'll have this secure.
-Yeah.
This has to work.
Oh.
We've got a big gap right
here that we're gonna have
to fill with a log or some.
This thing's worthless.
Rot, man..
Everything else here is
hard as a goddamn stone.
Ah, damn.
Screw that.
Just keep stacking
rocks up here.
Stop turning around.
You know, on day
one, this looked
like a really nice water source.
We were really excited about it.
Now I look at that water source
and I'm just, I feel scorned.
Oh man, oh man.
I'm about done
getting my ass kicked.
Right now, I'm thinking...
maybe South Africa and
me just don't get along.
South Africa is the only
country that's ever beaten me.
Oh, the pain is so bad.
On my first Africa
challenge, I was med-tapped
for bowel troubles.
That's the end of my challenge.
My second South African
challenge... I've got no food.
This is just terrible.
I decided to tap out.
-What's up, Wes?
-I'm going home.
-What!
-Soul crushing.
Absolutely soul crushing.
And so that is
motivation for me.
I'm doing everything I can.
It's time for me to
regroup and beat Africa.
Those high stress...
things just bring out
the absolute in me.
-Yeah.
-So I sincerely apologize.
Just a little more
humble now that...
I was an asshole.
So you can be the asshole.
Gosh, I've never been
the asshole before.
This is a first for me.
Mm, mm, mm.
I'm not sure I like it.
Stee, he's a great partner.
He's looking to take
care of me just a little bit
and I appreciate that sentiment.
So I came here
with one intention,
and that is to do
battle with South Africa
and come out successful.
Risking life and limb
to catch catfish.
Stee and Wes.
We're getting it done.
I stood my ground
against the elephant.
And it feels good to
do that, but I don't know
if I can sustain these
adrenaline rushes.
My body is weak, and it's
just not always your friend.
Like, adrenaline's there to
give you that boost of energy
when you need it to
perform beats like that.
It's depleting me
faster than I think
just operating normally.
Hell of a hot day.
It's, uh... it's time to go.
Full day of hunting
finally at a close here
and I didn't see
anything but, I mean it's...
it's warming up and makes
me feel good about the hunt
in the next few days.
There's a big snail right there.
You can't really tell
what the hell it is,
but that thing is huge,
look, that's my hand
next to that guy,
he's humongous.
Too bad... not edible.
Weighing over two pounds,
the giant African land snail
is almost 50% protein,
but contains many
disease-carrying parasites,
such as rat lungworm,
which can cause meningitis
if ingested by humans.
That would have
been a nice meal, but...
I'm feeling really confident now
that I just gotta
sit in the blind,
turn hunting into my
full time job out here.
I'm not willing to give up,
and, uh, I'm gonna get...
I'm gonna find myself
with the opportunities
I need to succeed.
Ugh...
I have determination.
I've been in combat zones.
I know what it means to maintain
a high level of focus.
This is just another
adaptation to that,
in a different environment.
So I know I can
do it. I won't quit.
I feel really good right now.
My determination will pay off.
I know it's gonna
swing the other way.
I know it will.
Goddamn it.
It is so dry out here.
I feel the water just being
sucked from my body.
Whew! Damn, that
helmet's getting hot.
Whew.
Lordy, lordy!
Each second that goes
by, it's getting hotter.
And it's been pretty
dead since day eight.
Day eight's the last
time I made a kill,
save for one catfish.
But that's completely changed.
It's just been a ghost town.
And nothing's moving, so...
I'm gonna call it for today.
I've been out here
for a couple of hours.
So I'm gonna take the
last few sips of water I have,
pack my stuff up, and
head back to the boma.
And that's it.
Story of my life.
Here we go, huh?
It's just been
relentless all day long,
and, uh, I'm tired,
thirsty, and I need shade.
I need to get back to camp.
Ow.
I already got something
in the bottom of my foot.
I can make it.
Ooh, yeah.
All right.
I've never felt
anything like this.
-Hey.
-What up, buddy?
Anything? Death Valley?
-Death Valley.
-I hear you.
I'm just day after day
after day after day after day
of nothing.
I'm wore out.
I just feel completely drained.
-I just got woozy as.
-Hey.
-Hmm?
-Woozy.
I just got woozy as.
Oh, lay down, dude.
Yeah.
Ah.
-I got the cold sweats.
-Oh, no.
Do you feel sick or
anything, or are you OK?
-Woozy.
-Yeah, you are sweating.
Yeah, you're turning white.
These nauseous, cold
sweats on the verge of fainting.
Um, and heat stroke
can kill you just as fast
as a leopard or a
lion can out here.
You OK?
Need the medic?
Camp to medic, camp to medic.
Yeah, I need the
medic down here.
I think, um, Frank
might have heat stroke.
I need somebody down here ASAP.
Frank being forced out
of a challenge would be
a crushing blow.
Camp to medic, camp to medic.
Yeah, I need the
medic down here.
I think, um, Frank
might have a heat stroke.
He's feeling really nauseous,
lightheaded, cold sweats.
I need somebody down here ASAP.
10, 4.
All right, so we were
closing out day 20,
and Frank got hit fast.
You know, instant
nausea, light-headeness.
He turned white as a ghost.
And it just goes to
show, Africa hits you fast.
And if you don't play
this the right way,
you can be out of here.
Hang in there, buddy.
Frank's symptoms could be
indicative of heat exhaustion,
requiring only rest and fluids.
Or it could be the early
signs of a heat stroke,
a much more dangerous
condition that can cause
loss of consciousness
and organ failure.
Frank's heart rate,
blood pressure,
and temperature are elevated,
but still within normal range,
and he'll continue to
be monitored closely.
Thank you, sir
-Thank you.
How you feeling, my friend?
Slushy.
One of the things
I've learned out here is
that a hero's role
isn't just to hunt and kill
and put stuff on the table.
It's to make sure
there is a pot of water
readily available.
It's to let your teammates
sleep on your shoulder
if they're exhausted.
And that's what I'm
gonna do with Frank.
I'm gonna take care of him.
I'm gonna make sure he's OK
because I'm not losing
my teammate this far in.
It was a major
eye opener for me.
We are getting late
in this challenge,
and this is an extremely
hostile environment.
We're just tucking in
for our last night here
at the, uh... at the boma.
Yeah, it's a little
bit bittersweet,
to be honest with you.
This place has
really looked after us
and, you know, put a
lot of effort, a lot of time
into building it the right
way, and that all paid off.
I'm gonna try to think
positively and imagine
that tomorrow is a lovely day
for a hike.
For now, we just get some rest.
So it is night 20, and
I am lucky to be here.
Came on quick.
One minute, I was...
fine, and the next, I was not.
Yeah, this is Africa.
It happens quick.
Today was a scary day.
So, from here on out,
we just gotta pay attention,
we gotta be careful,
we gotta be smart.
We gotta stay hydrated,
get rest when we can.
Yeah, I'm glad he's OK.
He's my little partner in crime.
Despite standing my
ground against an elephant,
my reward is to go
to bed hungry again.
That's all I have, is
the accomplishment
to comfort me now.
We got some new cause for alarm.
You know, the elephant
has been on my mind,
but now, in just a second,
you can hear hyenas
whooping and yipping.
I need sleep.
Shut up!
Oh...
Neighbors.
What are you gonna do?
Gonna show 'em who's boss.
Let's go before it gets too hot.
Let's do it.
First thing we do is
take the jerky down.
Great, almost 60 pieces.
Almost 60.
Day 21, right?
So a standard
challenge would be over.
We'd be extracting,
but not on this challenge.
This one is a greater
test of our resilience
and capabilities.
We've got two more weeks to
go, and we can't take those lightly
because the first two
weeks were excruciating,
and there's no reason
that the last two weeks
can't also be challenges
that will be hard to overcome.
And put that in your bag.
-That works.
-OK.
I like that.
We can make it so that we
can really cinch up the bedrolls
and get them out behind us.
Our tools, the ladle,
the hammer bolt,
the pliers, the hooks,
even the file, all of that,
we were able to tuck inside.
I was able to put my
mosquito net in there.
And so that left very little to
have to be carried in my bag
and in our hands.
So, obviously, we're down here.
What I was thinking is we
could just shoot this way,
hit this water source, and then
we can probably break it up,
and then we'll push up this way.
-OK.
-OK?
-Yeah.
-But if it does take us
three or four days,
that's just what it is,
-you know?
-Yeah.
I mean, we have plenty of time.
It's better to be
safe than laid out.
Yeah, absolutely.
From their current camp,
Waz and Teal plan to veer
northeast toward a
waterhole five miles away,
where they'll have to
make a temporary boma
and stay the night before
heading further north
toward a group of
larger waterholes
eight miles from the
edge of the wasteland.
Along this dangerous
trek, they will be stalked
by deadly predators at
every turn, including hyenas
with jaws powerful
enough to crush bone,
and the silent but highly
venomous puff adder,
capable of delivering
a painful bite
that can prove
fatal within minutes.
Putting some miles
on these puppies.
In order to get
close to escaping,
we absolutely should leave now.
But there's always concerns
about a journey like this.
This is a known place for us,
where we're staying right now,
and we're moving to an unknown.
I know there's gonna
be water, but I don't know
how hard it's gonna get.
I don't know how much we're
gonna have to push ourselves
to the limits, and maybe beyond.
-Think that's it, right?
-Yeah.
It's sad to go, but
this chapter's done.
We're turning the page,
and we'll see what else
we can find out there.
All right, bye, compound.
See you later, compound.
-Walking into the unknown.
-Oh, yeah.
I like it.
Yeah.
That'd be nice.
We still have to
be very cautious.
The croc is still here.
And uh, he was
moving in yesterday,
so he could be
anywhere right now.
We have to be super
vigilant, even though
we're looking forward
to a good meal.
We don't want to become a meal.
Bubbles?
Oh! Oh! Yes!
What you got?
You little! Got him!
Hold!
You are kidding me, dude.
Oh! Oh! Yes!
-What you got?
-You little!
Got him. Yes!
-Woo!
-You!
-You are kidding me!
-Yes,
You just hold on to him.
We've seen that before, right?
There's pure panic
in my veins right now
-that he's gonna drop the fish.
-Yes!
We cannot afford to
let that fish get away.
-After all this time, man.
-Oh, yeah.
You did it.- The
wriggly tin plan...
-it's worked out.
-Yes!
-Stee the Bull.
-A little small win.
That is so incredible, buddy.
Cut the head off and
do fish head stew after.
You do it right behind
that bone right there.
It's been a tough challenge.
Just trying to
survive one more day.
And then Stee catches a fish.
Yeah, mate. Look at that meat.
It's only a fish.
But yeah, when you're
this deep into a challenge,
every win is
extremely important.
It is an absolute mental
boost just knowing you're doing
something positive for yourself.
You did it.
No, we did it.
Take a little look.
All right, taste that.
We get taken all the way
down to the bottom, dude.
And then you catch a
break, last some more days.
Oh, man!
Oh, yeah. That's awesome.
-What a nice change.
-Mm.
It just tastes delicious.
Anything with
flavor tastes good.
And the fish just
tastes wonderful.
Yeah, you feel it
working on you instantly.
That's what we call picking
the bones clean there.
And you never guess
what. I caught a fish!
Come on!
This has just put us
forward by two, three days.
This is a good day.
Peace out. Love yous all.
I'll tell you what, Teal,
the sun is something else
-right now.
-You're telling me.
I feel like we did a great
job packing our stuff up,
but it's still super heavy.
Oh, my gosh.
I have a thorn in my foot.
Hold on, just a second.
The shoes we've
made are very helpful,
but they do not hold
up to things like big
buffalo thorns.
Oh, my gosh.
It doesn't make a difference
what you're wearing.
They're gonna shoot
straight through it.
Watch your step, there's
some big ones here.
-Yeah, there are.
-Humongous thorns.
It's all getting a bit
thicker, isn't it, Teal?
Yeah.
I'm just being careful
of where I'm walking,
but also keeping
my head on a swivel,
'cause who knows
what's out here, Teal.
Yeah.
Bushy trees here and shrubs.
You can't see very far.
There could be all sorts of
predators moving around,
and we wouldn't even
know they're there.
Oof!
All of the rest and
hydration absolutely did not
prepare me for this.
Oh my gosh!
I just keep thinking one
foot in front of the other.
This is way harder
than I expected.
Oh my goodness.
I don't have much more in me.
Let's keep pushing.
I know it's inevitable,
but, man, change is hard.
Oof!
Yep.
This is day 21, and you know,
this is a milestone for me.
This marks the longest
I've been on a challenge yet.
Normally I'm on my way out.
Yesterday afternoon
was, like, a bad day for me.
Just took a crash
and it was dehydration,
heat exhaustion, you know?
So I'm feeling much better today
after some rest and rehydration.
So we're just gonna keep
aligning the water and try
to catch one of these catfish.
Come on, as much
time as we've put in,
-we should be rewarded something.
-Right?
Frank seems to be
doing a little better.
I'm still concerned.
I'm gonna pay
close attention to it.
I'm gonna make sure that
he stays really hydrated
and stays in the shade
because otherwise we could have
a disaster on our
hands and I'm not losing
my teammate this far in.
We know they're in here.
We know they're
at least this big.
Yeah, I know.
And we know they
won't touch our lines.
That is so annoying.
That is very annoying.
Nuts.
Giant male elephant.
Crazy.
Yeah, it's
definitely not dinner.
When an African
elephant hinders the hunt,
it's time to pack
up and head back.
That's crazy.
Day 21, and no
opportunity, no animals.
Just Africa's telling us
we need to get outta here.
This location, especially.
All right, it's a fine time.
This is a new threshold.
This is the longest I've been
out on a survival challenge.
And I think my body
knows that we have crossed
into something
new, and I got a lot
of struggle happening.
Been sitting this blind
regularly for a few days now,
and I haven't seen anything.
But I know that I'm
a determined man,
and that the things that I set
my heart on, I accomplished.
Every day, I gotta be
back here in this blind,
watching this water hole,
hunting, hunting, hunting.
-Oh, I see water.
-No, really?
Oh!
-Wow.
-Yeah.
Wow.
Look at this. Fresh water.
It's actually really promising.
Huh!
All right, let's drop our stuff.
Oh, yeah.
I love the sight of this water.
OK.
-Well... -What?
-Oh!
Not what I expected to be
coming out of the bushes.
-Huh.
-Oh!
-Can I give you a hug?
-Yeah, of course.
-Yeah, yeah.
-What's your name?
-Joe.
-Joe, nice to meet you, buddy.
This is a whole
world changer for me.
You know, my mind has not
been set on social behavior.
It's been set on survival.
And so to see people come
out, like, that's a hard reset,
-This is your place, then.
-This is one of them.
I've gotta shelter up... up
the road a little bit, yeah.
Joe pops out of a blind,
and it came as a
complete surprise
as soon as I saw a head pop up.
And he seems, sort of, stoic.
And I don't know if that's
because he feels uncomfortable.
Whatever the case
may be, he doesn't seem
-very interactive.
-Where are your people?
-I am my people.
-You are your people?
So what's the story? How long
have you been by yourself for?
Day four. Lost both my partners.
-No!
-That's rough.
First impressions of Joe is,
you know, this guy's got grit.
Like, hats off to anyone
that can survive alone,
uh, for 17 days and be out
here in one of the harshest
environments in the world.
I give him mad
kudos for doing that.
-It's just you two then?
-Yeah.
And we decided, we're
gonna start heading towards
making our escape
here in the next few days.
Cool.
And you look like
you need some rest.
-Yeah.
-Have you swam in this?
Yeah, all the time.
It's so cold. Go for a swim.
There's a fish trap
from the tree in about...
-three or four feet.
-OK.
Going from standing
in that hot sun,
dripping with sweat and dust,
to embracing that cool water
was just so good.
Oh, it's way better
than it looks, too.
Every cell in my body
was just so thankful,
and I just felt completely
rejuvenated and replenished.
To be honest with you, man,
this has been the most savage,
been the most brutal, been
the most primal environment
that I think I've ever been in.
Yeah, no, not just
Africa... this spot.
-Yeah.
-This spot is void of life.
You have space
in your luxury suite?
I'd love to stay at least a
little while, but our plan is
to slowly make
our way to escape.
If you guys wanna stay, I mean,
I've got indoor fireplace,
I've got outdoor fireplace,
and I've got a
mattress, I've got a bed.
-OK.
-Yeah, definitely.
I'd love to stay at
least a night or two.
Teal and I have a plan.
Our plan is pushing
while we're healthy.
towards that escape point.
And we're gonna do
that over a series of two,
or three or four days.
Coming across Joe might
change that timeline a little bit,
but it's not gonna
change it a lot.
Do you have interest to
go check out this shelter?
-Yeah.
-Let's see what we've got up there.
All right.
As of right now, you know,
I'm getting a good vibe,
but I've been alone longer
than I've been with people.
So, I'm just trying to get a
grasp on them being here,
and we'll see where
it goes from there.
-You lead the way.
-OK.
Oh, man.
This is a real
strange turn of events.
What's up, fam?
-Hello.
-What's up?
How was it?
Oh, the same.
No guineas, no nothing.
I haven't seen anything
at the waterhole in three,
-four days.
-We need to do something.
It's been several
days now with no kills
and not seeing any game.
So we're dwindling
on our meat supply.
-Our biltongs are getting low.
-Yeah.
You know, there are two
things that are incredibly
concerning right now.
One is that we have
zero resources here now.
And that Frank is suffering
from heat exhaustion.
Well, it happened
quick, you know?
One minute I was...
feeling OK, the next minute
I was like, "What the hell
-is going on?" And then, phew.
-Yeah, that was scary.
That was really
scary, and that was just
-a big reminder.
-It was an eye opener.
I think we need to go
find another location.
As hard as it is to leave
the Thunder Bome...
Invested so much time,
so many calories into this,
for our survival,
we need to move.
As bad as I hate
to leave all this, uh,
it makes sense, you know.
We've made a mark
on the landscape.
Everything around
knows we're here.
What it does for me is,
it sort of, it does give me
a little glimmer of hope
because sitting here,
knowing that we
have zero resources
and not having any hope
that we're gonna catch anything,
-that can often be worse.
-Absolutely.
It's a risk versus reward
situation, but we either
sit here and die slowly or
we move to greener pastures.
If we get good rest, good
sleep, really good hydration,
it's gonna make it a lot easier.
-I think it's a good plan.
-We'll get it done.
Big moves.
What a difference
in terrain, man.
I mean, we were scorched
earth, too, but all this burnt bush
is just devastating.
Yeah, it's somewhat of a
"season of the stick's hell."
This whole area is just trashed.
I mean, after that big
rain, all of these brushes
and all of these small trees
should be shooting back
and growing, but they're not.
They're just absolutely wasted.
All right, welcome to the boma.
Yeah.
A little archway
to come in here.
This is fancy, bro.
-I like it.
-Yeah.
-You've done well.
-Yeah, all by my lonesome, too.
Wow. Look at that chair!
That's my chair
and my brick carrier.
Nice!
I'm very impressed with what
you've done with the place.
Thanks! Yeah, it's
a lot of hard work.
-Really get well insulated.
-Oh, I like it a lot.
Coming into this walk,
I was ready to build
a temporary boma tonight, go
on another big hike tomorrow.
Turns out, yeah, we
had that hard walk,
but we already have a boma
'cause Joe's boma's right here,
and he's invited us in.
So massive weight off my
shoulders for this night one.
Let me check the mail.
-No.
-Nothing today.
Nothing today.
Ta, ta-da!
I had to adjust
my social skills.
They're a little bit rusty,
like the rest of
the around here.
Have you been eating, or what?
-A little bit.
-...We got some jerky for you if you want.
-Jerky?
-We got a duiker.
-You got a duiker?
-Mm-hmm.
-Nice.
-We'd like to share.
Oh, thank you!
Oh, my God, that looks amazing!
Some of it is
gonna be pretty dry,
like almost bouillon, but...
Yeah, just let it
suck in your mouth.
All right, let me eat.
Having not had any red
meat for the past 22 days,
I need it so bad.
And I know my muscles are
being eaten by me right now,
so I think they
rejoice in the fact
that they might actually
get some nutrients
that could replenish them.
I savored every single bite.
I really appreciate this meat.
It really means a lot to me.
Of course, take
another piece or two.
I'm having a bit of
an emotional moment,
just like how good this
feels to have company
and to have a decent bite.
-What was the last time you ate?
-...Two days ago.
OK, what have you been eating?
Terrapin, catfish.
I hope I can get a terrapin
for you guys while you're here.
-I would love that, dude.
-It's such a good meal.
Can we get a good
fire going tonight?
Firewood's good.
So the nights here
can get kind of wild.
Sometimes it's real calm.
Sometimes you hear nothing.
Other nights, hyena and jackal.
And then, last night
was a lion, just right there.
-Oh.
-20 yards.
Oh, that's close.
My biggest concerns
about Joe's area is he says
that he's got lions coming
within 20 yards of his boma,
and all sorts of
other predators.
Perhaps his predators
are getting more bold
and aggressive, too.
This could be a
bad spot to be in,
but I'm going to do my
best to temper my fears
during the night.
Oh, feels good to sit.
Wow.
What a day!
All right, we are at the
Beaumont Chateau de Joe.
We are getting kind of
re-situated in his abode.
We have really
good shelter here.
We have warmth, we have
security, we have protection.
All the things that we thought
we were leaving behind,
and we have them again.
First night hosting guests,
and I built this
place for a team,
and it's great to
actually get a chance
to see how that
would have functioned,
and everybody's warm, and
dry and healthy and happy,
so it makes me feel good.
I'm getting a
little intimidated,
mostly because Joe has
said that there's so much
animal activity here,
but gonna have a fire
and hopefully a
good night's rest.
It's a super dark night out here
in the new place
that we're staying.
The window is nice
and the breeze is pretty,
but the dangers that out
there lurk are very scary.
So many new noises
and so very intimidating
to think about the things
that are walking around.
Trying to get some good sleep,
but all of the different noises
are definitely keeping me
on high alert.
We yell into the darkness.
That's what I did.
It worked out.
It was an eerie
night last night.
All the sounds
carried like crazy, man.
I could hear everything
going on for miles.
Last night, it was so noisy.
I feel like I could hear
everything, like grunts
and growls and purrs.
This place where
Joe is living is crazy.
Oh, wow! It's already
warming up pretty good, ain't it?
-Ooh!
-Yeah.
There's a little bit of
clouds, but every time
that sun peeks its head
out, it is all out here.
It feels like Terrapin Time.
The terrapin's the best
meal I've had out here.
But, you know, I've only
caught one in my fish trap
for the past 22 days.
We can use my mosquito
net and dredge the water hole.
Just one person on one end,
one person on the other end,
and we hold it tight
under the water
and hold it to the
bottom and sort of just
-push it through.
-Yeah, yeah.
Doesn't sound like there's
a lot of animals around here.
The only other food
source around here
that Joe's mentioned
is the terrapin
that are in the water hole.
I got the mosquito net.
We're gonna head down
that way with the mosquito net
and maybe dredge through,
or there's a chance that I just
jump on them and pull
them out with my bare hands,
just like we did
with the tilapia
over at our other water hole.
-There you go!
-OK.
Yes!
Lucky number 14.
This is gonna put some
fuel in the tank for us.
I don't know what
we're gonna do,
but we'll work it out,
and we'll get them
out of there somehow.
I wanna keep them in a bucket.
Hopefully, we get more than one.
-So they're squirrely.
-Oh, they are?
I'm really excited to
see their technique
using their mosquito net.
I'm grateful for them sharing
their meat, and I'm hoping
that we can score
some, and that I can share
what's in my pond with them.
Bring a bow and
arrow, just in case.
You never know what
we're gonna walk up on.
You never know.
-Ready.
Oh, it's my perimeter wire here.
For what?
Elephants, just
so I can hear 'em.
I thought, "Why not
give myself a little earlier
warning system?"
- You said "elephant"
-Elephant, yeah.
He's been super
aggressive with this area.
Sat there by the
water, and I was 25 feet
from an elephant,
stood him down,
and sent him back
into the woods.
Whoa.
That's my war
story, I'm very proud
I'm actually very, very
proud of what I did.
-It was really cool.
-It's crazy.
It's Joe's place.
Seems like it's getting
worse and worse.
He's got some
elephants come up close,
some lions will come up close.
In the back of my head,
I'm thinking, "What's next?"
All right, let's rock and roll.
No elephants today.
Nope, not today.
Terrifying.
I am ready to get
the heck out of here.
Today is the big
migration, and I'm hydrating,
packing to move.
Gonna take the bow and arrow,
of course, the man made items
that we did find, the knife
I found, and of course,
all our fishing gear.
I'm just gonna ball it up
the best I can, rope it off,
and make like a little backpack.
Gonna be heavy.
-Ow, Shh... -You all right?
-Yeah.
-beautiful.
-Thousand times better, right?
-Yeah.
-Sweet.
Hell yeah. Look at us.
Look like nomads.
Woo!
We ran out of resources.
We haven't had that much food.
We got to find somewhere new.
We got to find somewhere
where there is fish,
where there is
hunting possibilities.
And they're not here anymore.
All right.
That's our water source.
We need to go north where
these two water sources are.
More than a few miles.
From their current camp,
the team has targeted
a collection of large
waterholes over seven miles
to the north and
still eight miles
from the edge of the wasteland.
The difficult trek will lead
them through razor sharp
acacia thorn brush,
where lions lay in wait,
and herds of hippos
roam up to six miles a day,
able to reach speeds
over 30 miles an hour.
-Uncharted territory.
-Yep.
New beginnings.
We have no idea how long
we're gonna be hiking for.
we're gonna be out in the sun.
We have no idea if there's
gonna be any shade.
-All right.
-You guys ready?
-Yep.
-All right, let's do it.
All of the "uncontrollables"
are the things to be scared of.
Team Thunder Bome, let's do it.
See if we can wrangle
up some terrapin.
-Uh... -I think probably five or six.
-Yeah.
I was thinking if we could
just try to hit the corner.
To conserve energy and keep
cool in extreme temperatures,
many species of
terrapins in South Africa
burrow themselves
partially in the mud
along the pond floor.
So our plan of attack
in the water, Teal and I,
just gonna try and walk
this net through the waterhole
as much as possible,
one on each end of the net.
We're pulling nice and
hard on the bottom of the net.
It's going to drag along
the bottom of the water.
So we're basically just
drag netting back and forth
along the water hole.
It's not a huge water hole,
but it's definitely bigger
than the one we had before.
We're just gonna try to be
somewhat comprehensive
about how we cover the ground.
And we've done really good
being symbiotic in our work
over the last three weeks.
But this pond is
super hard to dredge.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
There's a lot more going
on underwater right here.
I got it.
Trying to take that out for you.
I realize, "Hey, if I get
all these thorn bushes
that are sticking
out of this thing,
they're gonna be able to
sweep this thing no problem."
So, just by seeing their
system and how it works,
I clear the way.
Trying to clear this.
Thank you, Joe.
I think we're getting
close, but it's not easy work.
Ooh, look at this.
Look at this, Teal.
Whoo!
...the bottom nice and tight.
-Whoo! Joe!
-Dude! There we go.
Oh, man.
We've got a terrapin in
the net, so it's a good start.
And we're going to keep going,
see how many we can get up to.
Yay! Oh, we did it! We got one!
-Got it!
-Yeah.
Yes, sir.
Teal and Waz working
together as a tandem duo,
they're just making
pass after pass,
and we are scoring
all kinds of meat
because of that
teamwork and camaraderie.
Wow, yeah, we got little mini.
All right.
Mwah! Thank you, bud.
Like, success and
positivity is such a rarity.
That's how I've
been living daily,
is that it's gonna suck,
and embrace the suck.
And so, when good things happen,
it's a total game
changer mentally,
that I'm still kind of
wrapping my head around.
Well, this is
actually a feast now.
OK, so back towards
that bank then.
Ugh!
I think we're draining
the pond here.
Tight all the way.
It's not easy, but
we just kept going.
We kept pushing, it was hard,
and eventually we made it work.
-Yeah.
-Good.
Yeah, we got three
littles and three bigs.
All right, well that
is certainly a bucket
-full of meat.
-There we go.
I don't know if I have
too many more in me.
I don't have much
more in me either.
-I'd like to stop.
-I got one in 22 days.
You guys get a
bucket in about an hour.
-That was just teamwork.
-100%, y'all.
We came out with
a nice little prize.
We've got six in there,
all different assortments
of sizes, but they're all
gonna taste just as good
no matter what size they are.
I can't wait to share
this meal with you guys.
All right, we're gonna
start prepping this.
All right. Cut these
guys out here.
Just slide it. There you go.
There we go. OK.
Goody gumdrops. All right.
Chop heads, crack shells.
Teal and I got six terrapin
out of that water hole.
I'm happy to share all of that.
There's three of us, so
that's a nice, even balance.
All right.
Liver, stomach.
The fat's the tastiest bit,
but It's also the bit
that we really need.
You know, fat's
the thing that allows
your brain to take over.
So the more diminished
your fat intake is,
the less you're able
to problem solve.
And problem solving is
the thing you have to do
to be able to survive, so,
getting that fat,
allowing that brain to start
ticking again, it's
absolutely integral
to being successful in the
last couple of weeks here.
Yeah, come try this. Trust
me, it's worth the hype.
Get some water.
To the even side, too,
which is much better.
Oh, yeah.
Cheers!
First meal, caught
and shared together.
-Ooh, that's tasty.
-Isn't it?
-Ooh.
-Told you.
Somewhere between
chicken and pork, man.
Oh, yeah. This is really good.
Really creamy.
Six terrapin out of
Joe's pool of water
is pretty enormous for him.
He hasn't eaten like this
in the whole challenge.
A hot meal, in addition
to the jerky, is certainly
gonna give him more
energy to go forward.
I really do appreciate it.
Just want you to know
that. I was so hungry.
Yeah, the sun's out now.
Holy crap.
We're gonna roast.
It's definitely Africa.
The heat came out.
Yeah, it did.
I mean, when it's like
90 in the shade, it's just...
You know, when
the sun comes out,
the lions hide in the shade
and there's shade
everywhere here.
So they're gonna be as
active as we are today.
You know, the thing is
out here, the animals,
we might not see them,
but they definitely see us.
It's like anything
could be hiding in there.
You wouldn't see it
until it was too late.
Yeah.
Whew!
I may have overloaded
my pack a little.
My pack was probably the
heaviest one in the camp,
but because of these
man-made materials, you know,
I just didn't want to leave
any of that stuff behind.
Oh, goddamn.
I mean, who knows
what we'll find out there
for the next location.
It might be the difference
between completing
this challenge and failing,
But this is
absolutely miserable,
carrying all that weight.
Ugh!
-You all right, Frank?
-Yep.
-Hanging in there.
This stuff's cutting into
my shoulder pretty bad.
This is horrible.
Whew!
Oh, wow.
Keep following this game trail.
You guys doing
all right back there?
No.
I got a pounding headache.
Ugh, goddamn.
Frank's not doing well.
The only other time I've
seen him struggle like this
was the day he
got heat exhaustion.
And I'm really concerned.
He's finding it difficult
to navigate the terrain.
Oh, nice.
He's looking more and
more sunburnt every time
I look at him, and
sweat is pouring off him,
-which is a real concern.
-Ugh!
-Is there anything I can do?
-Nope.
Just need shade and water.
All right, guys, let's get
some water real quick.
Whew!
Frank's tired.
The heat exhaustion
that he experienced,
it worried all of us, and
we're in for a long hike.
We've already been hiking
for God knows how many miles
for multiple hours, but all I
can do is lead by example.
-Everybody hydrated?
-Yeah.
I know it's hot. I
know the sun's out.
We're burning
through it, though.
-I'm sweating.
-Yeah, I just wanna get this done now.
Back on. Let's do it.
There's an opening up there.
We just gotta keep
following this riverbed.
It's gonna...
it's gonna happen.
Every step forward
is a step closer.
Yeah, I'm.
Yeah, hot and
juicy, too, you know?
This is just gonna
give us that little boost.
It's gonna push us up.
It's gonna help us get
through to the next goal.
Whenever we decide to
pack up and leave outta here,
I'm sure you wanna
come with us, right?
I will eventually.
Yeah, I need some
time to hunt, to get that.
I want that blind to
work. I want it to produce.
When was the last time you
saw something from the blind?
Like an edible animal?
Long time ago.
Gotta see animals
to hunt, though, man.
I'm a determined dude, you know?
I gotcha.
Hearing Joe's stories, he
sits around 10 hours a day
just to see something,
not to get a good shot,
but to see something
he could shoot.
Here's the reality...
is there's nothing here.
Good luck, though.
Thank you, see you soon.
I wanna think about
getting on the road.
I wanna know
where your head's at.
I wanna get on the
road, too, but I really think
-that Joe should come with us.
-Mm.
But I think his brain
is still really wrapped
around hunting here.
I haven't seen an animal
since we've been here.
No, and I didn't think
it could get any worse.
And then we got here,
and I was like, "Oh, no."
Like, I really don't
see any scat piles.
I don't see any prints.
There's nothing here. Nothing.
Want Joe to come with
us as well, but I think
we've got to get on the road.
Let's put a hard and fast on it.
What day are we leaving
here by, with or without Joe?
I think we gotta get
out of here tomorrow.
But in the morning hours,
before it gets too hot.
OK, I'm good with that.
All right, well,
we'll have a chat
with him when he
gets back, and we'll see
-where his head's at.
-Yeah.
Maybe he's not comfortable...
We'll just, you know, part ways.
I feel like Joe has
been imprisoned
by his own solitary lifestyle.
Because he's been alone so long,
he's turned into
a hermit of sorts,
and he's very much
stuck in his current routine.
He has to break through it,
but the truth of the matter is
that Joe has to
wanna do it himself.
We can't make him.
Well, I'm back.
Back here in this blind.
I know they're out here.
It's just a matter of
putting in the time here.
The next few days, this
place is gonna become
a really desirable spot.
Whew!
Come on, come on.
OK.
Whew!
-That is hot.
-It is really hot.
There's really no
shade out here.
-Big thorns coming up.
-Nah.
Ouch!
You guys doing
all right back there?
Yep.
Let me tell you, I am wore out.
Everything hurts, from
my head to my feet.
Ah!
-You all right?
-Yeah.
Damn.
We're close, guys, I feel it.
-Whoa, watch the thorns.
-Yeah.
The trail's getting
harder and harder to...
-navigate, like much narrower.
-Ah!
Definitely bigger rocks.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, more green.
All right, there's definitely
another water source.
We're experiencing
these different terrains.
We're following
these riverbeds, right?
I'm trying to find um,
these two water sources.
Elephants have definitely
been here, pushing over
-all these trees.
-We gotta find water.
We definitely
need to find water.
That's gotta be number one.
Oh, thank God, it
looks like it opens up.
Oh, and there's the water.
Oh! There it is.
Looks like we made it.
We come across a
magnificent water source,
that is huge, and
this place looks primo.
Now, this is a water hole.
Look at this. This
isn't a water hole.
What in the... hang on.
What's in the mi...
those are hippos.
Oh, my God! there's
a giant hippo out there.
Holy.
Look at that monster.
So, I'm trying to make
the smallest hook possible
and the sharpest hook possible.
Fortunately, this
wire is really old,
and I'm really hoping that I
can put a nice fine edge on it
for a fishing hook.
So having to make
fish hooks out of old wire
is really difficult.
I mean, if you have
manufactured stuff,
it's laser sharp.
And so the slightest tug,
it just penetrates into a fish
or a terrapin's jaw.
Uh, this, not so much.
OK, and there's about as
small as a bush fish hook
you can get out of just wire.
Come on, team. Get some catfish.
How's your new hook?
-Uh, I like it.
-Yeah.
I like it.
Come on, little fish.
All it takes is one.
Holy.
Look at that monster.
-Oh, my...!
-Hippos are assholes.
Get catfish down here.
I'm gonna get eaten by a hippo.
As soon as we kind
of come over the ridge,
I see this absolutely
enormous bull hippo
pick his head up out of
the water, flap his ears,
and just death stare us down.
Is he looking right at us?
-100%.
-With his little eyes up?
-Oh, yeah.
It is incredibly territorial.
They kill more people
than lions out there.
Yep.
One of Africa's
deadliest animals,
hippos have the jaw strength
three times that of a lion.
Their poor eyesight make
them skittish by nature,
leading to highly aggressive
and territorial behavior.
-Jesus!
-Oh, wow!
I think it's a big
male and a female.
So I'm gonna be catfishing
at the other end of the river.
It doesn't matter where you go.
No, they move.
And they come out at night.
-Yep.
-No.
And if you're in between
them and the water hole,
they'll trample you
and gore you to death.
I think we have to keep going
and find the next water hole.
-One without hippos?
-Yeah.
I completely agree,
it's unsafe we stay.
Though the hippos
kill people all the time.
On first sight, we were like,
"Oh, my God! This is
a massive water hole."
And I'm thinking, "Finally,
I'm gonna catch bloody fish."
To see the hippos
pop up, my heart sinks,
none of us wanna keep going,
but to make a home
here would be suicide.
It looks like there's a
game trail that keeps going.
-Yeah.
-And I'm guessing, you know, all game trails...
-Lead to water.
I wanted this journey
to be over so bad,
but when I seen them
hippos, I knew there's no way
we can stay here, and
that was just soul crushing.
All right, guys,
let's get out of here.
We're making them upset.
This is not a safe place.
This is not where we're staying.
-No.
-We'll die.
-On to the next one.
-Let's go.
It's getting late.
He is watching us leave.
This sucks.
Oh, man. I'm getting hot.
-Hey, buddy.
-Hey.
-How you doing?
-Good, you?
Doing good.
See any animals down there?
-Not a damn thing.
-Nothing.
Well, Teal and I
had a conversation
while you were down the water,
and we've made the decision
we have to leave.
We gotta go.
We need to get back on track.
It's not about staying
and doing anything.
It's about moving
on, it's a long way
-to the next waterhole.
-Yeah.
Apart from the turtles,
I haven't seen an animal
since we've been here.
So we're wanting to push
through and see if there's
a place with a lot
more opportunities.
We would love to
have you come with us.
No?
There's nothing here.
If we go forward to
this oasis or something,
and it's got more water,
to me, that's...
its... harder target.
-Mm-hmm.
-I wanna continue to fight
and get really beat this place.
That goal still seems
attainable to me.
They may not see it.
They don't know how big
of a commitment to my heart
it has been to
succeed at this task.
So when they wanna get
out of here, I understand.
It is not a desirable place.
But my heart belongs
here with my task,
with what I wanna
do, with who I am,
and how I accomplish my goals.
This isn't to try and force
your hand or anything.
If you think this water hole
owes you an extra
couple of days,
we're gonna be
leaving without you.
We just have to have... we have
to have a hard, hard line on it.
Think about it.
I don't know yet, but we'll see.
We'll see what happens.
This land, it can consume you,
and it's already started on Joe,
but if this wasteland takes him,
it's not taking me too.
-Yeah.
-You never know.